字幕来自 godort
是，我们会把他安排妥当的
Aye, we'll sort that out for him.
咱们周一早上真得早点了
We've got to get started really early on Monday, though.
我会告诉他的
I'll talk to him about that.
亲爱的，你能出去买包烟吗？
Go out and get us some fags, love, would you?
好吧
Yeah.
克里特，去吧
Collette, get going.
给你自己买点糖
Get yourself some sweets?
抱歉，老兄，嗯
Sorry, mate. Aye.
出了夫人之外，现在还没有人走
No one's heading out now except for the missus.
爸爸让你去买烟呢。-他叫你去的
- Dad wants you to get some fags.- He asked you.
那怎么了，上次是我去的
It doesn't matter. I went last time.
喝牛奶吗，克里特？-不喝了
- Do you want a glass of milk, Collette? - No, I'm fine.
睡觉之前别忘了刷牙，亲爱的
Don't forget to brush your teeth before you go to bed, love.
去呀。-不去
- Go on.- No.
我给你点钱
I'll give you some money.
别说了，该走了。-嗯，我这就来，这就来
- Stop talking and get ready.- Aye, I'm coming. I'm coming.
给我买点糖
Get me some sweets.
快跑！快！他们来了！
Run! Come on. They're coming!
妈！爸爸！
Ma! Dad!
上帝呀！他被枪打了，天呐！-怎么回事？
- Jesus Christ! He's shot. Jesus.- What happened'?
他被枪打中了，爸爸。-什么？谁？肖恩？
- He got shot, Dad. - What? Who is it? Sean?
是肖恩吗？天呐，格里
Is it Sean? God, Gerry.
呼吸！看在上帝的份上，呼吸！
Breathe, for Jesus' sake, breathe.
去拿个毛巾
Get a towel. Get a towel.
躲开！
Get out the way!
呼吸，呼吸！
Just breathe. Just breathe for me.Go on, please.
快给我，快他妈给我
Give that to me. Get the fucking...
天呐！
God.
格里
Gerry.
我的天呐
Jesus Christ. Jesus.
肖恩，肖恩，天呐，肖恩，天呐
Sean, Sean. God. Sean, Sean. God.
肖恩
Sean.
天呐
God. God. God. God.
坚持住，肖恩
Please, God. Sean. God, no.
不
No.
借过
Excuse me.
小心月台与车厢的缝隙
Mind the gap.
女士们，先生们，请注意
Ladies and gentlemen,your attention please.
紧急通知
Due to a reported emergency,
请所有乘客立即离开站台
will all passengers leave the station immediately?
女士们，先生们，请注意
Ladies and gentlemen, your attention please.
紧急通知
Due to a reported emergency,
请所有乘客立即离开站台
will all passengers leave the station immediately?
你要水还是咖啡？
Do you want water? Coffee?
找不到你要的资料
It's not gonna give you what you want
你们的律师需要的资料也没有
or what your family's lawyers expect.
不过这可能会有帮助
But it might help.
一时半会儿且完不了呢
This could take a while.
你在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
我可不这么想
I doubt it.
好
OK.
那么，你知道我们已经掌握了这些情况
So, a lot of this you know we know.
有些情况你还是不了解
Some of it you definitely don't.
比如说这个，记得他吗？
Like this. Remember him?
你肯定认识
'Course you do.
看着他
Look at him.
亨利·劳斯，你在他的印刷厂工作过
Henry Laws. You used to work in his print factory.
你告诉的康纳，他是预备役军人
You told Connor he was a part-time soldier.
你负责侦查，格里下的命令，康纳开的枪
You scouted it. Gerry ordered it.Connor pulled the trigger.
亨利的妻子在尸体中找到了他们的孩子
Henry's wife found their kids clinging to the corpse.
很显然他的家人不知道，但一周之后
Now obviously his family didn't know,but a week later,
你参加了葬礼，为什么？
you went to the funeral.Why did you do that'?
好吧，看看临时取证
OK. Provisional forensics.
这可不是为了把你的兄弟们弄回来准备的
This is definitely not one for the brothers back home.
这份东西将会带出很多棘手的问题
This would definitely lead to a lot of awkward questions.
我猜你可能想的是
So I guess this is how you figured it.
你放下包，打个电话，他们发出警报
You leave the bag. You make the call.They place a warning.
火车上有个炸弹
There's a bomb on a train somewhere on the line.
我们必须把整个铁路网关闭
We have to close down the whole network.
我们找到了炸药包，把它拿到安全地点引爆
We find the bag.We carry out a controlled explosion,
这是的兄弟们在家完全想不到的，对吗？
and that way your brothers at home never find out, right?
你根本就没装定时器，克里特
You never set the timer, Collette.
我想请个律师
I want a lawyer.
作为一个恐怖分子不能让自己……我要找个律师
- A terrorist who can't bring herself to...- I want a lawyer.
我告诉你你会被怎么处置吧
Let me tell you what it's going to be like.
爱尔兰姑娘，蹲英国监狱
Irish girl. English jail.
每次你想见你儿子或者你儿子想见你的时候
Every time you want to see your boy,every time he wants to see you,
孩子他奶奶就会带着他乘坐渡船航行400英里（643公里）过来看你
his grandma's gonna have to load him onto the ferry and drive 400 miles.
这会让他很伤心的
It's gonna break his fucking heart.
你知道你的兄弟们去年杀了多少人吗？
Do you know how many people your brothers killed last year?
今年这些牺牲者仍然或者，克里特
This year's victims are still walking around, Collette.
他们洗衣服……
They're doing the washing.
把孩子放在学校里
They're dropping their kids at school.
你完全可以让他们保持现状
You can keep it that way.
你知道，现在所有人都在谈论和平
You see, now that everybody's talking peace,
这个词就是你们这些头领觉得格里的问题所在
the word is that your leaders think that Gerry's the problem.
他不想让这种事发生
He's not going to let them sell out.
那么他到底想干什么？
So how far is he gonna go? What's he gonna do?
你如果同意去监视他并且向我们报告，
You agree to watch him and talk to us,
你就可以像什么都没发生过一样离开这儿
and you're out of here like nothing ever happened.
回到你的母亲还孩子那去
Back to your ma. Back to your boy.
我们会付钱给你
We'll Pay you...
以后如果你想离开这儿，我们会想办法把你送走
And one day, if you want it, we'll give you a life far away from this.
不会有人死
Nobody dies.
不会有人受伤
Nobody gets hurt.
我们只需谈谈
We just talk.
我要请个律师
I want a lawyer.
这不是你的风格，克里特
This isn't who you are, Collette.
你他妈怎么知道我什么风格？
How the fuck would you know who I am?
我连怎么弄坏的
I know it bugs the hell out of you
你妈妈的洗衣机都知道
that your mum won't get the washing machine fixed.
我还知道你一直纳闷你儿子为什么还在尿床
I know you're asking yourself why your boy still wets his bed at night.
去你大爷的！
Fuck off.
而且我还知道你来这之前很孤独
And I know you were so lonely the night before you came down here
甚至把一些你根本不喜欢的男人带回家
that you went home with some guy you don't even like.
我要找个律师
I want a lawyer.
你想请多少律师都行
You can have all the fucking lawyers you like,
但是有一件事是改变不了的
but it's not gonna change a thing.
我们抓住你了，你完了
We've got you. You're finished. You're done.
你儿子也完了
So is your boy.
你瞧
Look.
这是一份管束你儿子的文件
There's the paperwork to have him taken into care.
你真想找个律师吗？你真想走这条路？
You really want a lawyer? You wanna go that way?
拨9就是外线
Just dial 9 for an outside line.
是的，爱尔兰共和军继续坚称这是出于和平的目的
Yes, the IRA does continue to insist it's serious about peace,
但是这种口号将渐渐失去民心
but a lot of people are going to find that hard to credit
共和军组织试图派来
when the organisation appears to be trying to send
一切青年男女到这里来
young men and women over here
在伦敦的交通运输系统中释放人体炸弹
to place bombs on the London transport network.
目前，警方怀疑这张照片上的人
And now the police have issued this photograph
就是今晚的炸弹释放者
of the alleged bomber tonight.
照片有些模糊
It is a little indistinct.
这是在她进入隧道之前被监控拍下的画面
It was taken from the security camera before she went into that tunnel,
但警方希望有人能通过这张照片认出这个人
but they hope that someone will recognise her from it.
现在，播放其他新闻
Now, in other news,
政府将在今天的晚些时候做出决定……
and the government is expected to give its decision later today...
他们会杀了我
They'll kill me.
他们不会知道的
They'll never know.
他们会的
They will.
我会在那24小时监视的
I'll be there, day and night, watching.
你以前这么干过吗？-是的
- Have you done this before? - Yes.
他们后来还活着吗？-是的，都活着呢。
- Are any of them still alive? - Yes, all of them.
直到你不再需要他们为之吧
Till you don't need them any more.
我们是一起行动的
We do this together.
但是我得听你说出来
But I need to hear you say it.
你得想好了
You have to be sure.
我想好了
I'm sure.
这是我们的暗号，记住它，然后把它烧了
So this is our number. Memorise it, then burn the paper.
所有事都要听迪克兰的
Always ask for Declan.
他是你的新男朋友，那是你的掩护身份
He's your new boyfriend. That's your cover story.
我们在每周三的午夜时分见面
So we meet every Wednesday at midday
地点在皇后码头的停车场，从这周开始
at the car park in the quay at Queen's Island starting this week.
你就在那溜达就行了，我会找到你的
You just walk around until I find you.
你要是觉得有人跟踪你就一直走，别停
You think you're being followed, don't stop.
用房间里的座机
Don't use the phone at the house.
要是有人看见你在电话亭里，就告诉他们是给你男朋友打的
Anyone sees you in a phone box, just say it's a love affair
你不想让你妈妈听到
you don't want your mother to hear about.
你会用得上这个的，这是一个紧急呼叫器
You're gonna need this. It's an emergency bleeper.
把它藏好
Hide it well.
你按下这个扭之后，很多人就会展开行动
You press that button, half the world will come running.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
什么事都要问迪克兰
Always ask for Declan.
我是说你的真名
I mean your real name.
你不知道最好
It's better you don't know.
你要是出了差错，我就完了
If you make a mistake, I'm dead.
是吧？
Right?
我想知道你的真名
I'd like to know your name.
麦克
Mac.
那么咱们就后天在码头见了
So I'll see you at the quay the day after tomorrow.
你可一定要去啊
You make damn sure you're there.
他在哪呢？-在后院玩儿呢
- Where is he? - He's out the back.
他没事
He's fine.
马克
Mark.
走开
Go away.
嘿，过来。-走开
- Hey. Come here. - Leave me alone.
过来，过来
Come here. Come here.
没事了
You're all right.
我看看
Let's see.
我看见了，一，二，三，四，五……
I can see one, two, three, four, five...
你们怎么样？我听说我们的姑娘回来了
How youse all doing? We heard a rumour our girl was back.
嘿，格里。-嘿，妈妈
- Hi, Gerry.- Hi, Ma.
嘿，康纳。-嘿，妈妈
- Hi, Connor.- Hi, Ma.
见到你很高兴，-见到你很高兴，最近怎么样？
- Good to see you.- Good to see you. How's it going?
新闻上都说了
It was all over the news.
对咱妈好点儿，她最近情绪不太好
So just be careful with Ma. She's been a bit upset.
你怎么样啊，小人儿？-我和爱尔兰总理一致同意
- All right, wee man? - The Taoiseach and I are agreed
在北爱尔兰问题上发出联合宣言
on a joint declaration on Northern Ireland.
绝不妥协，坚持原则
It makes no compromise on strongly held principles.
你听见了吗？-哦，我在报纸上看了
- You heard about this, right? - Aye, I read about it.
我们的要求简洁而清晰，抵制暴力行为
Our message is clear and simple. There is no future in violence.
共和党领导人连姆·休斯做出了回应
Republican leader Liam Hughes gave his reaction.
共和党人对此感到十分失望
Republicans are very disappointed about what they've heard here today,
但是我们会慎重考虑这份协议
but we will give this document serious consideration
并且对此做好了推动的准备
and stand ready to move the process forward.
但在此后……
But even after...
把胡萝卜吃完
Finish your carrot, there.
写作业之前想踢会儿球吗？
Want to play some football before you start your homework?
好啊
OK.
那，怎么了？你被跟踪了？
So, what, were you being followed?
不是全天候的
Not all the time.
我觉得他们在火车上安排了人
I think there was some of them on the train,
所以我下车跑了
so I got off and ran.
跑进隧道了了？-嗯
- Into a tunnel? - Aye.
有胆无谋
Brave. Stupid.
你应该跟凯文谈谈
You'll need to talk to Kevin.
累死我了
Jesus Christ.
他没事了，挺好的
He's all right, so he is.
你怎么样？
How are you?
我没事
I'm fine.
我瞧瞧
See that.
格里说什么了？
What did Gerry say?
我应该跟凯文谈谈
I have to talk to Kevin.
为什么？
Why?
因为格里说了
Because Gerry says so.
家里这边怎么样？
How are things here?
挺好的，很平静
It's OK. It's quiet.
你还记得皮尔吗？
Remember that peeler who tried to put us away
把咱们从印刷厂赶出来那个
for your boss at the print works?
我们现在知道他住哪
We know where he lives.
也许你礼拜五应该来
Maybe you'd like to be a part of it.Friday.
我回房间了，格里，作业还没写呢
I'm going up to my room, Granny. I've got to do my homework.
可以走了，先生
There you go, sir.
嘿。-好的，帕特，谢谢
- Hey.- OK, Pat, thanks.
恭喜。-你的注意
- Congratulations. - Your idea.
但是你去抓捕的
But it was your catch.
她真的参与行动了吗？-看看就知道了
- Is she really in? - We'll see.
他们会让她越过凯文马尔维尔
Well, they'll run her past Kevin Mulville.
他们现在比以前更疯狂了
They're even more paranoid than normal at the minute.
没事儿，她很聪明，会有办法的。-那就好
- It's OK. She's smart. She'll be fine.- Good.
走了。-拜
- Have a good day.- Bye.
一会见
See you later.
操
Shite!
我跟康纳说了把它修好
I asked Connor to fix that.
咱得把格里叫回来，妈
We need to get Gerry in, Ma.
康纳连自己的头发都搞不定
Connor can't fix his own hair.
她不来
She's not coming.
嘿，格里。-嘿，亲爱的
- Hi, Granny.- Hi, love.
有人找你
You have a visitor.
嗨，马克，你怎么样？
All right, Mark. What about you?
还好吗？
Are you all right?
你好，凯文。-克里特，你怎么样？
- Hello, Kevin. - Collette, what about you?
嘿，你先去，我马上就来
Hey, you. I'll be there in a second. Go through.
你儿子真不错
That's a beautiful wee young fella you have.
有点像你，凯文
That's kind of you, Kevin.
咱们得谈谈伦敦的事儿
We just need to talk about London.
待会的，我得给他泡茶去
Later. I've got to give him his tea.
志愿者从不推卸责任，克里特
A volunteer is never off duty, Collette.
一个母亲也不会，凯文
Neither is a mammy, Kevin.
好吧，没问题
All right. No problem.
那咱明天再说。-嗯
- Tomorrow, then.- Aye.
他来干吗？
What the fuck's he doing here?
他是爷爷，康纳，他正要走呢
He's grand, Connor.He was just leaving.
我正在做我的工作，康纳。-去你妈的，上别地儿做去！
- Just doing me job, Connor.- Fuck off and do it somewhere else.
明天见，克里特
See you tomorrow, Collette.
傻逼
Prick.
这儿可没有他可干的事
He's no business coming to this house.
你好，格里。-凯文
- All right, Gerry? - Kevin.
你是来找我的吗？-不是，克里特叫我来的
- Are you looking for me or something? - No, I was just calling in for Collette.
格里可真不懂事
Gerry should be keeping him in line.
她眼里只有她的儿子
Her hands are full there with the young fella.
妈妈 -马克
- Mummy? - Mark?
我能吃点蛋糕吗？-可以
- Can I have some cake? - All right.
开门！警察
Open up! Police!
妈！
Ma!
妈妈！-你们不能就这么闯进来
- Mummy! - You have no business breaking in here.
你以为你是谁呀？-穿上衣服，麦克维小姐
- Who do you think you are? - Get dressed, Miss McVeigh.
马克在哪？-穿上衣服。
- Where's Mark? - Get dressed.
别抓她，听着，我们受够了
Leave her. Leave her alone. Look, we've had enough.
我们受的苦够多的了。她还有个孩子需要照顾呢，天呐！
- We've all had enough. - She's a mother, for God's sake.
我也有个孩子，那又怎样？
I'm a fa, but what does that change? Nothing.
让她先穿好衣服
Well, let her get dressed.
你是有个儿子吗？麦克维夫人？
Are you looking after the boy, Mrs McVeigh?
妈妈。-马克，天呐！
- Mummy? - Mark. Jesus Christ.
过来，快点，你个小混蛋
Come on, hurry up, you wee bitch.
妈妈1-没事的，儿子
- Mummy! - You're all right, son.
快点！-过来，亲爱的
- Come on! - Look, come here, love.
没事的，亲爱的
It's all right, darling.
别挡道
Get out of the way.
好了，马克，马克
All right, Mark. Mark.
没事，亲爱的，没事。-妈妈！
- You're OK, darling. You're OK. - Mum!
把她带出去
Bring her out.
快点，自己走两步儿
Come on. Move yourself.
你怎没去呀？
Where were you?
我得照顾我儿子，走不开
I was looking after my son. I couldn't get away.
我把你从终身监禁的惩罚里解救出来
So I save you from a lifetime in a prison cell,
你跟我这儿假门假事地说你不能来接头
and you're seriously gonna sit here and tell me that you didn't turn up
就因为你他妈找不到一个保姆？
because you couldn't find a fucking nanny?
你有一分钟的时间告诉点情报
You've got one minute to give me something,
否则咱们的协议作废
otherwise the deal's off,
而且你会在走廊里看到你的被指控文件
and you're down that corridor looking at a charge sheet.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你见到你那些兄弟了吗？
Have you seen your brothers?
嗯
Aye.
格里是怎么看那份宣言的？
What does Gerry think of the declaration?
没什么看法。-他是怎么说的？
- Not much.- What did he say about it?
我不知道
I don't know.
有天下午他在你家附近出现了
He was round your place the other afternoon
就在那份文件被签署之后，新闻上现在全都是这个
just after the document was signed. It was all over the news.
他对此怎么看？
What did he say about it?
告诉我他有什么行动，运作，计划之类的
So tell me what's moving. Operations, plans.
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道么？
You know what?
这样可不行
This isn't gonna work.
你还是找个律师吧
You need to call a lawyer.
明天……
There's something tomorrow.
康纳想要把我们支开
Connor's going to get the detective
去杀印刷厂的老板
who tried to put us away for the murder of my boss at the print works.
在哪？-我不知道
- Where? - I don't know.
什么时候？
What time?
他没说，我知道的就这些了
He didn't say. That's all I can tell you.
他说他已经跟詹金斯说了
He said he was called Jenkins.
他问我上周都去哪了
He wants to know where I was last week,
都干什么了
what was I doing?
好吧，咱们再来一遍
OK, let's go over it again.
我记住了
I've got it.
好吧，他们不会马上来找你
OK. So they might not come at you straight away,
所以小心点，别放松警惕
so be careful. Don't drop your guard.
好了，该走了
OK, it's time to go.
你该走了
You should go.
妈妈
Mummy?
我尿床了，对不起
I wet my bed. I'm sorry.
别担心，没事的
No worries. You're all right.
他没事吧？
Is he OK?
嗯。-他都好几个月没尿床了
- Aye.- He hasn't done this for months.
克里特，如果你不告诉格里你不想干了
Collette, if you won't tell Gerry that you've had enough,
我会告诉他的
I will.
嘿，杰夫，你今天早上还去伦敦吗？
Hey, Geoff. Are you still going to London in the morning?
不去了，我得参加一个TCG的紧急会议
No, I got pulled into this last minute TCG meeting.
什么会？
What meeting?
可能只有受邀请的才能参加吧
Guess it's invitation only.
这不扯淡呢么，你们不会是认真的吧
Please tell me this is bullshit. You can't be serious.
你们把英国空军特种部队都搬到他的后院去
You're going to put the SAS in his back garden?
德里克·汉德森是我们自己人
Derek Henderson is one of our own.
我们不能坐在这就为……-告诉他吧
- We can't just sit here and... - Tell him.
你要这么干的话，咱们的线人就死定了
You do this, our player's dead.
听着，我们有个机会
Look, we have a chance here
能把康纳·麦克维一网打尽，我们必须抓住这个机会
to take Connor McVeigh's entire team out of circulation, and we have to take it.
你们设这么一个套，这些人的父母都会被牵连进来
You lay an ambush, there'll be the mother and father of all tout-hunts.
干脆把她的名字直接发到贝尔法斯特去呢
You might as well print her name in the Belfast fucking Telegraph.
别冲动
Come on. You're overreacting.
我得给伦敦打个电话
I'm gonna call London.
在我跟布坎南谈过之后，所有事都给我暂停
I want everything on hold until I've spoken to Buchannan.
我已经跟他谈过了，麦克
I've already spoken to him, Mac.
这他妈都怎么回事啊？-我怎么知道
- What the fuck is this all about? - How should I know?
你把康纳·麦克维的消息给我们，我们把他拿下
You give us Connor McVeigh, we're gonna take him.
剩下的是你自己的问题
The rest of it is your problem.
克里特？-我操
- Collette? - Jesus fucking...
几点了？-六点
- What time is it? - It's 6:00.
怎么了？
What's going on?
布莱恩·弗林昨晚上被抓了，我们需要你
Brian Flynn was picked up last night. We need you.
我跟马克保证过要送他去上学
I promised I'd take Mark to school.
妈妈会带他去的
He's fine with Ma.
起来吧，穿好衣服
Get up. Get dressed.
不行，康纳，我都跟马克保证过了
No, I promised Mark, Connor.
是不是出什么事了？
Is something wrong?
没有。-穿衣服
- No. - Get dressed.
汉德森的车每天早上七点
Henderson pulls out of a cul-de-sac off the Newtownards Road
会从新唐纳德路一条死胡同里开出来
at 7:30 on the nail every day.
他的车是一辆银色的格拉纳达
He drives a silver Granada.
咱们分别把住两边的出口，布兰登去做事
You block one side, we block the other and Brendan does the business.
明白了吗？-嗯
- Have you got that? - Aye.
你们要是想喝咖啡也行
Youse can have coffee, if you prefer.
放下吧
Put it down.
康纳，我去趟厕所
Connor, I'm going to the toilet.
克里特，你完事了吗？
Collette, are you ready?
我找迪克兰
I need to speak to Declan.
克里特？
Collette?
克里特，你没事吧？
Collette, are you ready?
克里特，克里特
- Collette? - Collette.
听好，我得跟我的兄弟们出去一趟
Listen, I've had to come on a wee trip with my brother.
我在里边，我在里边
I'm inside. I'm inside.
不
No.
你没事吧？
Are you OK?
嗯，没事
Aye, I'm fine.
该走了。-好
- We're ready.- Right.
拿着这个，跟我一块来
Put this on. You're coming with me.
什么？-你跟着一起去
- What? - You're coming with me.
我的天呐！出去！出去！-我的天
- Jesus Christ! Get out! Get out! - My God.
妈妈
Mummy!
钥匙呢？钥匙呢？
Where's the key? Where's the fucking key?
在我丈夫那儿
My husband has the key.
有什么消息吗？
So what have you got? Anything?
枪手的名字叫布莱登·奥谢。他在重症护理病房
The shooter's name is Brendan O'Shea. He's in intensive care.
很难说他能不能被抢救过来
It's touch and go whether he'll make it.
马维尔呢？-我们还在找
- Mulville? - We 're still looking.
好
OK.
真他妈操蛋
What a fucking mess.
感谢你能来，巴里
Thanks for coming by, Barry.
回见
Talk later.
得拉文之前是什么？
What was all that with Delavine earlier?
是不是感觉被排挤在外了？麦克？
Are you feeling left out, Mac?
这么说你是从另外一个角度办案的？-不是
- So you're working another angle? - No.
别担心，我们还是一拨的
Relax, we're all on the same side.
我找迪克兰。-稍等
- Can I speak to Declan? - Hold the line.
对，我是迪克兰
Yeah, this is Declan.
他死了吗？
Is he dead?
他在医院，不过伤得挺重
He's in the hospital,but it's not looking good.
我给你打电话的时候他进来了
He came in when I was talking to you.
他听见你打电话了？-嗯
- Did he hear you? - Aye.
好，我们会处理的
OK, we'll deal with it.
如果他能活着，仅此而已
If he's alive, that's it.
我说了，我们会处理的
I said we'll deal with it.
好吧，好吧
Right, right.
凯文
Kevin.
咱们得谈谈
We need to talk.
嗯。-现在就说
- Aye.- Now.
随便坐吧，克里特
Have a seat there for yourself, Collette.
喝咖啡吗？
Do you want a coffee?
来一大杯
Be grand.
第一次听说手术是什么时候，克里特？
When did you first hear about the operation, Collette?
今天早上在车里。-早上在车里？
- This morning in the car.- In the car this morning?
嗯。-你确定吗？
- Aye.- Are you sure about that?
嗯
Aye.
之前没提到过吗？-没有
- No mention of it before then? - No.
康纳给了你点线索？-没有
- Connor drop you a few hints? - No.
用不用我们把那个想要把你带走的家伙处理掉？
We were going to take out the guy who tried to put you away?
不用
No.
是这样，克里特
See, it's like this, Collette.
只有两个人知道行动的时间和地点，对吧？
Only two men knew the time and the place, right?
格里不可能说出去
And it's hardly our Gerry squealing to the Brits.
那么，是不是他那个毛头小子兄弟干的？
So, is it his shaggy-haired brother?
或者是他跟他妹妹说了
Or did he blab his fat mouth off to his sister?
我们在伦敦把你跟丢了
We lose you in London,
但是你之后又跟没事人似的回来了
but then you're back like nothing ever happened.
然后警察就去敲你妈妈家的门
Then the peelers bash in your Ma's door,
把你抓到卡斯尔雷去了
haul you off to Castlereagh.
结果你下午就回来了，就跟什么都没发生一样
But you're back by tea time,like nothing ever happened.
他们知道我离开了一阵子
Sure they knew I'd been away for a while.
谁？-一个英国人
- Who? - A man. An English fella.
他叫什么？-詹金斯
- What was his name? - Jenkins.
ML5？-有可能
- Ml5? - Probably, aye.
他想干吗？
What did he want?
我在哪？我都干些什么？
Where was I'? What had I been doing?
你怎么说的？
What did you say?
我说我去南边看我的姑妈
I said I was visiting my auntie in the south.
没带着儿子？
Without your son?
我告诉他有人跟我一块去的
I told him I was going with a fella there.
是谁叫你干这些的？-麦克
- Which one asked you about it all, now? - Mac.
麦克是谁？
Who's Mac?
你不是说他叫詹金斯吗
You said his name was Jenkins.
他的全名是麦克·詹金斯
Well, Mac Jenkins, that's his name.
那你跟他还挺熟的咯？
So you were friendly then?
叫得这么亲密
First name terms and all that.
你危险了，克里特·麦克维
You're red-lighted, Collette McVeigh.
别离开贝尔法斯特，你的事还没完呢
Don't leave Belfast. We're not done yet.
他在哪？-他正在跟上帝忏悔呢
- Where is he? - He's making his excuses to our Lord.
太愁人了，是吧？
So sad, isn't it?
他说他想再跟克里特谈一次
He said he wants to talk to Collette again.
这可不行，格里。你得让凯文撤回来
That's not right, Gerry. You need to tell Kevin to back off.
这事出了之后，他得再跟她谈谈
After what's just happened, he'll need to talk to her again.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
我在医院听说布兰登死了
Just heard from the hospital.Brendan's dead.
天呐
Christ.
是你杀了他吗？
Did you kill him?
是你把他杀了吗？-冷静
- Did you fucking kill him? - Calm down.
没有
No.
你是不是想杀他？
Were you going to?
凯文知道了，他警告我了
Kevin knows. He's red-lighted me.
他不知道，他想诈你
No, he doesn't. It's his job to make you think he knows.
这种事他最拿手了
Well, he's brilliant at it then.
你说过不会死人
You said, "Nobody dies",
不会有人受伤。-克里特
- "nobody gets hurt".- Collette!
克里特，亲爱的
Collette, love.
人真他妈多
Fucking loads of them.
你会跟他们谈谈吗？
Do you want to talk to these guys?
我会去的，好吗？
I'll do the talking, OK? Yeah?
你们得让我们过去
Youse will have to let us through.
早上好，我们不能让你们过去
Good morning. We agreed none of this would happen.
我们还就得过去。-你知道这是违法的，休斯先生
- Yes, we did. - You know the law, Mr Hughes.
是，我知道。-那就好
- Yes, I do.- Good.
你不能为一个平民开脱，在我这行不通
You're not going to bury this man as a soldier. Not on my watch.
这什么也没有。-那是个有色政党
- There's nothing here.- That's a colour party.
那只是一些缅怀逝者的人
It's a few grieving men.
你觉得我好骗是吗？
Do I look like I was born yesterday?
你们把气氛搞得太敌对了。我们不会惹麻烦的
Do you realise how antagonistic this is? There'll be no trouble from us.
走吧，格里。-听着，我们不想惹麻烦
- Come on, Gerry. - Listen, no trouble...
我们得保证安定团结
Just make sure there isn't.
格里
Gerry.
走开
Walk away.
把你的人带走，听见了吗？
Move your men back. Do you hear?
保持警戒
Stay where you are.
想想办法，利亚姆。-你知道我没办法
- Better stand in, Liam.- You know I can't.
圣父，圣子，圣灵
Father, Son and the Holy Ghost.
上帝啊
For God's sake.
利亚姆
Liam.
有什么要说的吗，休斯先生？
Any comments, Mr Hughes?
看这儿，利亚姆
Look over here, Liam.
你好吗？
All right?
你怎么样？-你还好吗？
- What about you? - What about you?
康纳在哪？-我觉得他可能在后边
- Where's Connor? - I think he's in the back room there.
好，-嗯
- Right.- Aye.
再见，咱们一会见。-没事，保重
- See you. I'll see youse in a wee bit. - No bother, take it easy.
今天的事搞得我们很被动，知道么？
What happened today makes us look bad, understand?
这让我们内部产生分歧
It makes us look divided.
你们现在想停火
Youse want a ceasefire now.
我们还没说到那一步呢，格里
We're not there yet, Gerry.
我们没到那一步，但你们到了
We're not there, but youse are.
英国人正在谈一件很严肃的……
The Brits are talking about a serious...
一份投降协议，那就是谈判的内容
A document of surrender,that's what's on the table.
英国人在针对我们的行动
The Brits are talking about a serious response
做出很坚决的回应。-那是一份停战协议
- to any gesture we make.- It's a document of surrender.
你说的不对，你错了
You've no fucking right. No fucking right.
这是大头儿的决定，格里，你不能有疑议
- The leadership decides, Gerry. - You don't represent us.
你决定从来就没对过
You never fucking have.
这是大头儿的决定。-从来就没对过
- The leadership decides.- Never fucking have.
这是领袖的决定，格里
The leadership decides, Gerry.
你现在给我冷静点，傻逼孩子
Now cop yourself on. Fucking child.
嘿，你好，老兄
Hiya. How you doing, man?
嘿，小妞，你好吗？-很好
- Hey, pet, are you all right? - All right.
你出来啦，克里特？
You away there, Collette?
嗯，已经开始了
Aye. Aye, it's getting on.
别忘了给可怜的布兰登的父母一点尊重
Don't forget to pay your respects to poor Brendan's parents.
实际上，我想问问你，凯文
Actually, I've been meaning to ask you, Kevin.
你现在是在保护我的兄弟吗？
Are you my brother's keeper, now?
我会尽力保护他们的，克里特
I'll do what I have to do, Collette.
今天是你儿子的生日吧
I believe it's your wee boy's birthday.
给他买个足球什么的
Get a football or something.
谢谢你了，凯文。-没事
- That's kind of you, Kevin. - Don't worry about it.
请出示证件，先生
Identification please, sir.
好了，谢谢
That's fine. Thank you.
麦克？
Mac?
进来
Come in.
进来说吧
We'll go in here.
路易
Louie.
你先出去
Can you give us a minute
去别的屋跟你爸聊会儿去
and go and talk to Daddy a minute in the other room?
好了，喝什么？-不用了，谢谢
- Right, drink? - No, thanks.
行了，这可是周末
Come on. It's the weekend.
我要知道你是一个人就请你过来了
If I had known you were on your own,I would have invited you over.
你为什么把汉德森的文件锁起来了？
Why have you locked the Henderson file?
也许是伦敦的案子。-不是伦敦的
- Maybe it was London. - It wasn't London.
巴瑞·德莱文是跟我一拨的
Barry Delavine works my side of the street.
如果他被调到你手下
If he was pumping your hand,
那就说明他对汉德森的案子有了其他的办法
that means he's got another angle on Henderson.
其他的办法的意思是其他的情报
Another angle means another tout.
你找了其他的人、-麦克
- So you got someone else.- Mac.
但是找克里特·麦克维是你的主意，现在我不明白了
But Collette McVeigh was your idea, so I'm asking myself why.
你知道么，我花了八个月的时间让她刺探情报
You know, I spend eight months reeling her in,
但是你一开始就想置她于死地，为什么？
and you're prepared to burn her on day one. Why?
我会告诉你原因的
I'll tell you why I think.
我认为麦克维就快拿到巴瑞的情报了
I think Mulville was getting close to Barry's tout,
结果你弄来一帮傻逼跟着瞎搅合
and you just wanted some fucking red meat to throw him.
我想把她摘出来。-那不可能
- I want to take her out.- That's out of the question.
听着，他们会认为她为我们工作，这样无论如何
Look, they'll assume she's one of ours, so she'll still take the heat off
她仍然能得到你的保护。-别做梦了
- whoever it is you're trying to protect.- That's fantasy.
而且，她还仅仅是开了个头
Besides, she's only just got started.
她把我们交待的事情都做了。-行了，麦克
- She's done what we asked of her.- Come on, Mac.
一个新身份，新护照，一所房子和一份收入
A new identity, protection, a house,income for life.
这得多少？一百万？
What is that? A million?
就为了让她当了八个月的卧底？
Throw into that eight months' work setting her up.
别傻了
It's more like two.
你以为伦敦方面会仅仅因为
You think London's going to buy all that
对康纳·麦克维的帮派的一次袭击就全部买单吗？别做梦了
just for one good hit on Connor McVeigh's crew'? Forget it.
我们可是有言在先。-我不会允许的
- We made a deal.- I absolutely forbid it.
凯特，她还有个儿子呢
Kate, she's got a son.
你是不是迷上她了，麦克？
Is this because she has a pretty face, Mac?
我觉得你没那么傻啊
Because I thought you were a lot smarter than that.
喜欢吗？
Do you like it?
来啦
There you go.
你猜这是什么？不想打开看看吗？
What do you think that is? Are you just gonna look at it?
他根本就没动。-打开它，马克
- He's doing nothing.- Open it, Mark.
来吧。-拆开看看
- Go on.- Open it up.
看。-把包装撕掉
- Look.- Just rip it off.
包装还挺结实的，是吧？
It's quality wrapping right there, isn't it?
快呀，撕开它
Go on. Rip it open.
看呐。-你喜欢吗？
- Look at that.- Do you like it?
很不错吧？-是啊
- It's a good one, isn't it? - Yeah.
你觉得大小合适吗？-我觉得没问题
- Reckon you're big enough for it? - I think so.
这车很快的。骑起来很快，知道么
It's very fast.A very fast bike this, you know.
我来检查一下
I'm just gonna check the old...
看上去不错
It looks good.
好了，骑上吧
All right, get up on it.
好了，我撒手了啊。耶！
OK, off you go. Yeah!
太好了！
Yes! Perfect.
转个圈。闸好使吗？-好使
- Turn round. Is the brakes all right? - They're fine.
试试闸，骑到这然后捏闸
Check them when you... Just try them out down here.
慢点，别停，别停……
Slow it down. Keep going. Keep going.Keep...
很好，现在是上坡了
Perfect. It's all uphill now of course.
他骑得真不错。-有模有样的
- He's doing all right. - Looks great.
我觉得咱们这个礼物算是送对了。-可不是么
- I think we done a good job there. - I think so.
骑快点儿。-你看他那小脸儿
- Just go faster. - Look at his face.
再快点儿。-加油
- Faster. - Come on.
加油，很好。-马克·麦克维
- Go on. Perfect. - Mark McVeigh!
马克？
Mark?
好，加油，好的，20秒
Right, come on. Right, 20 seconds.
21秒，躲开那里，好的
Twenty-two seconds, off you go.There you go.
非常好……
That's all right. That's 20...
别说了，妈，求你了，至少今天别说
Don't start, Ma, please. Not today.
回来，你上哪去？
Come back now. Where you going? That's 23...
你要去哪啊？他这样会摔着的
Where you going? He's gonna kill himself.
让他停下，不，停，停，停……
Stop him going. No, stop.Stop, stop, stop.
你来这儿干嘛？麦克。-帮我个忙
- What are you doing here, Mac? - I need a favour.
你都退出这个项目很久了
You were all out of those a long time ago.
他们正在找格里·麦克维的情报，对吧？
They're hunting a tout in Gerry McVeigh's crowd, right?
有一阵子了吧？
Have been for a while?
快一年了
Maybe a year.
他们知道有人跟格里很熟
They know it's someone close to Gerry.
格里什么反应？
What's Gerry doing about it?
他听取了我们的朋友凯文·马尔维的意见
He's listening to our friend, Kevin Mulville.
你认识马尔维，麦克
You know Mulville, Mac.
除非他把某人杀掉，否则他是不会善罢甘休的
He won't stop until he's put a bullet in someone's head.
我一会就回来
Be back in a wee bit.
我约了看医生
I have a doctor's appointment.
你不能带上马克吗？
Can't you take Mark with you?
你去哪？-郊区
- Where are you going? - Downtown.
等一等。-求你了，妈，我得走了
- Then going downtown can wait.- Please, Ma. I've got to go.
你去郊区干吗？克里特？
What are you going to do in the town, Collette?
别问了，妈
Please, Ma.
你用不着去郊区。-我得走了
- No one has to go downtown.- I've got to go.
你迟到了。-我这不来了么
- You're late. - I'm here. I've made it.
你要见我，我就来了，我妈为此很生气
You've seen me. I've got to go.My mother's raging.
克里特。-凯文盯上我了
- Collette. - Kevin's watching me.
听着，咱们以前就这么干都没事。-天呐
- Look, we've been through this before. - For Christ's sake.
听我说。你还有工作要做。-我的工作就是摆脱这些
- Listen to me. You've got a job to do. - My job is to end up in a ditch.
不，你还没干完呢。-我干完了
- No, it's not going to end up like that. - Aye, it is.
你要振作起来，否则这根本无济于事
You've got to pull yourself together, otherwise this isn't going to work.
你自己选吧
You made your choice.
我完了，我完了，我自己选了一条死路
I'm dead. I'm dead.That's the choice I've made.
不，你不会完的
No, you're not. That is not gonna happen.
我会保护你的
I'm not gonna let that happen.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我得把你带出去
I've got to take you out.
现在只有我帮你了，明白吗？
It's just me, you understand?
他们有自己的计划，如果我要把你带出来，我们只能靠自己
They've got their own agenda, so if I take you out, we're on our own.
我需要几天的时间
I'll need a few days.
我可以带上你儿子，你明白吗？
I can take your boy but nothing else, you understand?
你明白吗，克里特？
Do you understand, Collette?
礼拜一的三点我在这等着
I'll be here at 3:00 on Monday.
肯定的，政客说的全都是谎话
Sure, the politics of it is all bollocks.
要是真这么来，我们自己搞都比这个强
If it comes to it, we'll go our own way and be better for it.
但是我们身上要背着事儿就什么都干不了
But we're nothing if we're not clean.
情报上说咱们有案底
And a tout means we're dirty.
格里，我撑不了多久
Gerry, I can't hold on any longer.
咱们都不行
We can't.
肯定是你身边的人告的密
It's someone close to you. It has to be.
你得跟我保证
I need the word now.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
你好，杰夫，我是麦克。-嘿，麦克
- Hello, Geoff. It's Mac.- Hi, Mac.
听着，我正在写一份报告
Yeah, listen, I'm just doing a bit of paperwork here.
你知道汉德森的那个案子吗？
You know the Henderson operation last week?
他们有没有把硬拷贝存进档案室里？
Do you know if they've put a hard copy in the library yet?
不清楚，怎么了？
Not sure. Why?
我进不去档案
I can't seem to get in.
你能把密码告诉我吗？
You couldn't dig me out the agent code, could you?
你记一下。-好的
- You got a pen? - Yeah, shoot.
实际上，有两份报告
Actually, there's two on the incident report.
那就对了，把两份都给我吧
That's all right. Just give me them both.
672545 'I/MIU
5736917/LPN.
咱们再说一遍好吗，康纳？
So let's try this one more time, Connor, '?
你什么时候跟你姐说的袭警的事？
When did you tell your sister about the attack on the peeler?
去你妈的
Fuck you.
继续
Go on.
好吧
All right.
你要是没告诉她就说明你是那个告密者，康纳
If you didn't tell her, then that means you're the squealer, right, Connor?
帮我个忙。-你怎么老有要帮忙的事呢
- I need a favour. - You always need a favour.
我要找一份卡斯尔雷的录音
I need to look at some of the records from Castlereagh.
为什么？
Why?
我要查一下82年四月所有的审讯记录
I want to check out everyone that was brought in for interview or interrogation
为什么？
- around April '82. - I said, "Why?"
你知道他们多谨慎吗
You know how uptight they are.
帮帮忙，伊恩。咱们各司其主，对吧？
Come on, Ian. Everyone's got to fight for their guy, right?
这事瞒不了多久了
I don't think mine's got long left.
最后一次机会，康纳
Last chance, Connor.
杀了我吧
Just fucking do it.
来呀
Fucking do it.
他不是我们要找的人
He's not the one we're looking for.
82年几月？-4月
- '82. What month? - April.
拿去吧
Get on with it.
快点，你们该晚了
Come on. Youse are going to be late.
你刷牙了吗？-刷了
- Did you clean your teeth? - Yes.
我接
I'll go.
给你外套，妈妈。-谢谢你，马克
- Here's your coat, Mummy. - Thank you, Mark.
你好。-他们去找克里特了
- Hello? - They're coming for Collette.
我们让她来保护你
We recruited her to protect you.
好，我们这就走
Right, off we go.
不知道是谁。-回见
- There was nobody there.- I'll see you later.
再见，奶奶。-过来，马克
- Bye, Granny. - Here, Mark.
再见
See you.
我们能及时赶到
We made it in time.
你应该看看他在门口那张小脸儿
You should have seen his little face at the gates.
妈？
Ma?
妈妈，咱们这是去哪啊？-咱们来一次小小的旅行
- Mummy, where are we going? - We're going on a wee trip.
康纳？-结束了
- Connor? - It's done.
咱们得走了
We need to get going.
Subtitles by @godort